<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide Istanbul</string>

    <!-- Categories -->
    <string name="category_historical_place">Historical Place</string>
    <string name="category_must_visit">Must Visit</string>
    <string name="category_entertainment">Entertainment</string>
    <string name="category_restaurants">Restaurants</string>
    <string name="category_hotels">Hotels</string>

    <!-- Historical Places -->
    <string name="hagia_sophia">Hagia Sophia</string>
    <string name="hagia_sophia_info">
        Often referred to as the eighth wonder of the World, the Hagia
        Sophia (Ayasofya in Turkish) in Sultanahmet is easily one of Istanbul\'s most impressive
        sights. It also must have one of the most turbulent histories of any museum in the world.
    </string>
    <string name="hagia_sophia_address">Sultan Ahmet Mahallesi, Ayasofya Meydanı, 34122 Fatih/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="blue_mosque">Blue Mosque</string>
    <string name="blue_mosque_info">
        The Blue Mosque was built between 1609 and 1616, by the architect Mehmet Ağa, instructed by
        Sultan Ahmet I. It was designed as an imperial show of strength to complement the imposing
        Hagia Sophia, which faces it across Sultanahmet Square. It is dubbed the Blue Mosque because
        of over 20,000 handmade ceramic Iznik tiles that decorate the interior, featuring many
        different tulip, rose, carnation, and lily designs, well lit by 260 windows.
    </string>
    <string name="blue_mosque_address">Sultan Ahmet Mahallesi, Atmeydanı Cd. No:7, 34122 Fatih/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="rumeli_fortress">The Rumeli Fortress</string>
    <string name="rumeli_fortress_info">
        Rumeli Castle (Rumeli Hisarı) is an Ottoman fortress dating to 1452. It was built by Ottoman
        sultan Mehmed II (Mehmed the Conqueror) in preparation of the conquest of Constantinople.
        The castle is situated on the shore of the Bosphorus Strait at its narrowest point with approximately
        660 meters. It is just opposite of Anadolu Castle (Anadolu Hisarı) that is another Ottoman castle
        built in 1394 by Bayezid I. Both Anadolu Castle and Rumeli Castle were built by Ottoman sultans
        in order to prevent military and economic aid to the Byzantine Empire coming from the north, Black Sea.
        Thus, Bosphorus strait connects Black Sea with Marmara Sea.
    </string>
    <string name="rumeli_fortress_address">Rumeli Hisarı, Yahya Kemal Cd., 34470 Sarıyer/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="basilica_cistern">Basilica Cistern</string>
    <string name="basilica_cistern_info">
        Known locally as Yerebatan Sarayi (meaning Sunken Palace) or Yerebatan Sarnici (Sunken Cistern),
        this underground water cistern was the major water reservoir of Constantinople. The water was
        transported from the Belgrade Forest by the immense Byzantine aqueducts.
    </string>
    <string name="basilica_cistern_address">Alemdar Mh., Yerebatan Cd. 1/3, 34410 Fatih/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="dolmabahce_palace">The Dolmabahce Palace</string>
    <string name="dolmabahce_palace_info">
        The palace was commissioned by Sultan Abdülmecid (who decided there should be a more European
        palace than Topkapi) and designed by Armenian architect Karabet Balian and his son Nikoğos Balian.
        It is an ostentatious blend architectural styles including Baroque, Rococo, Neoclassical and
        modern Ottoman, dripping in luxury.
    </string>
    <string name="dolmabahce_palace_address">Vişnezade Mahallesi, Dolmabahçe Cd., 34357 Beşiktaş/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="archaeology_museum">Istanbul Archaeology Museums</string>
    <string name="archaeology_museum_info">
        The İstanbul Arkeoloji Müzesi (Istanbul Archaeological Museums) complex is one of the most
        underrated museums of Istanbul, and actually consists of three museums: the Archaeology Museum,
        the Ancient Orient Museum, and the Islamic Art Museum. It has founded by master painter, Osman
        Hamdi Bey in 1875, in a response to the removal of many of Turkey’s ancient artefacts destined
        for European museums. There is a wealth of treasures on show from the Assyrian, Hittite, Egyptian,
        Greek, Roman, Byzantine and Ottoman civilizations. The below are a few of the collections and items not to miss.
    </string>
    <string name="archaeology_museum_address">Cankurtaran Mh., 34122 Fatih/İstanbul</string>

    <!-- Must Visit -->
    <string name="maidens_tower">Maiden\'s Tower</string>
    <string name="maidens_tower_info">
        This unique tower with a history dating back to 2500 years,
        has eye witnessed everything that the city has encountered throughout the history.
        This tower has been erected during the ancient age and constructed by renovations from the ages of the Ancient Rome,
        the Byzantine Empire, and the Ottoman Empire, the tower has reached to present time with its mysterious appearance.
    </string>
    <string name="maidens_tower_address">Address: The Maiden\’s Tower is located 150 200 meters off
        the shore of the Salacak district in Üsküdar.
    </string>
    <string name="haydarpasa">Haydarpaşa Garı</string>
    <string name="haydarpasa_info">
        Haydarpaşa Garı, Istanbul\'s Teutonic pseudo-castle railway station
        on the Asian shore of the Bosphorus was the terminus for suburban trains and trains to and
        from Anatolia (Asian Turkey) for over a century.
    </string>
    <string name="haydarpasa_address">Rasimpaşa Mahallesi, 34716 Kadıköy/İstanbulı</string>
    <string name="istiklal_street">Istiklal Cd., Bryoğlu/ İsstanbul</string>
    <string name="istiklal_street_info">
        Istiklal is both local and touristic center of Istanbul. It\'s the heart of the city.
        Many people have a love/hate relationship with the ever-bustling (Istiklal Street or Istiklal
        Avenue – İstiklal Caddesi in Turkish) that runs from Taksim Square nearly all the way to the
        landmark Galata Tower. Although it is the beating heart of the city, the three million people
        that pass it every day, can make it rather challenging to traverse. Yet it serves as a microcosm
        of Istanbul itself and although chains and fast food joints are starting to edge out the more
        old fashioned shops, there’s still traces of old Istanbul here.
    </string>
    <string name="istiklal_street_address">İstiklal Street</string>
    <string name="moda_tea_garden">Moda Tea Garden</string>
    <string name="moda_tea_garden_info">
        A sprawling tea garden perched on a hill above the Bosphorus,
        Moda’s tea garden is one of the city’s most popular destinations. A scenic ferry boat ride away
        from the bustling hubs of the historic peninsula, Galata and Taksim, Moda and its environs are
        a welcome alternative to Istanbul’s busy central district and its tea garden is perhaps one of
        the most serene parts of inner-city Istanbul.
    </string>
    <string name="moda_tea_garden_address">Caferağa Mahallesi, Park İçi Yolu, 34710 Kadıköy/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="ortakoy">Ortaköy</string>
    <string name="ortakoy_info">
        Seen from the Bosphorus cruise, the Bosphorus coastline on the European side resembles a string
        of villages, each with their own individual character and attractions, and indeed that’s just
        what it was. Located between down-to-earth Beşiktaş and chichi Kuruçeşme, Ortakoy does what its
        name suggests and positions itself somewhere in the middle (orta köy means ‘middle village’ in Turkish).
    </string>
    <string name="ortakoy_address">Ortaköy Mh. Beşiktaş/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="miniaturk">Miniatürk</string>
    <string name="miniaturk_info">
        Ever wanted to see the sights of Turkey, but don’t have the time? Maybe you need some help
        preparing your Turkish itinerary? Then perhaps Miniaturk is the answer.Opened in 2002 on the
        Golden Horn, the world’s largest miniature park contains 105 miniature models in 1/25th scale
        of well known Turkish historical sites in an open air expanse. Covering an area of 60,000m2,
        Miniaturk offers dwarfed versions of famous sights including Hagia Sophia , Topkapi Palace, 
        Blue Mosque, Nemrut Dag, Artemis Temple and even a walkable Bosphorus Bridge.There is a c
        oin-operated cable boat which travels across a pond and a miniature train.
    </string>
    <string name="miniaturk_address">Sütlüce Mahallesi, İmrahor Cd. 7/1, 34445 Beyoğlu/İstanbul</string>

    <!-- Entertainment -->
    <string name="sortie_night_club">Sortie Night Club</string>
    <string name="sortie_night_club_info">
        Sortie, means ‘Exit’ in French, is a great place to let it
        all hang out. ‘Togetherness’ is the key word in our 3500-square meter venue. Since 2012 we
        began to serve 12 months of the year and host 7 restaurants that represent distinguished examples
        of the world cuisine. Sortie Club offers the latest trends in the world of entertainment to you
        at the same time, Dj Tarık SARUL’s the coordination of the music continues to entertain for 12 months.
    </string>
    <string name="sortie_night_club_address">Muallim Naci Cad. No: 54 Kuruçeşme İSTANBUL</string>
    <string name="ulus_29">Ulus 29</string>
    <string name="ulus_29_info">
        On the sea side of Ulus, inside Ulus Park, Ulus 29 is chosen by many locals as an example of
        Istanbul’s best defining venues. The one-of-a-kind water view can be seen from inside Ulus 29.
        The menu is a complilation of dishes from worldwide cuisines; with different flavours from
        yoghurt kebab to lahmacun, sushi to peking duck. While listening to music from around the world,
        you may opt to have a glass of French wine with your meal.
    </string>
    <string name="ulus_29_address">Kuruçeşme Mahallesi, 34345 Beşiktaş/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="jolly_joker_istanbul">Jolly Joker Istanbul</string>
    <string name="jolly_joker_istanbul_info">
        Located centrally in Beyoğlu, Jolly Joker Beyoglu spans over 1000 m2 and is able to host up to 800 people.
        In terms of technique, acoustics and service, Jolly Joker Beyoglu is one of Beyoğlu\'s top venues. Jolly Joker
        Beyoglu hosts live concerts focusing mainly on big names in the Turkish music scene.
    </string>
    <string name="jolly_joker_istanbul_address">Hüseyinağa Mahallesi, Balo Sk. No:22, 34435 Beyoğlu/İstanbul</string>

    <!-- Restaurants -->
    <string name="lacivert_restaurant">Lacivert Restaurant</string>
    <string name="lacivert_restaurant_info">
        Lacivert marries the rich and exquisite flavours of the Mediterranean cuisine which include centuries
        of culture and taste, at Istanbul’s most romantic and picturesque coastal view, on the one and only
        Bosphorus. Located within a historic seaside-mansion, Lacivert has become a true Bosphorus-classic,
        serving guests since 1999. The idyllic Lacivert terrace becomes an ideal spot during the summer season,
        hosting the perfect balance between the summer Sun and the warm sea-breeze. During the winter season,
        Lacivert remains as charming by entertaining guests in saloons over-looking a sentimental sea-front view of the Bosphorus.
    </string>
    <string name="lacivert_restaurant_address">Anadolu Hisarı Mh., Körfez Cd. 57/A, 34410 Beykoz/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="leb_i_derya">Leb-i Derya</string>
    <string name="leb_i_derya_info">
        Leb-i Derya is located on the top floor of an unassuming apartment block on
        the hillside road of Kumbaracı, just off the bustling İstiklal Caddesi. From the street, the entrance is
        located at the foot of a somewhat-dilapidated building and you will have to take two flights of stairs and
        a lift to reach it, but you will not be disappointed.
    </string>
    <string name="leb_i_derya_address">Şahkulu Mah., Kumbaracı Ykş. No:57, 34425 Tünel/Beyoğlu/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="kasibeyaz_bosphorus">Kaşıbeyaz Bosphorus</string>
    <string name="kasibeyaz_bosphorus_info">Kaşıbeyaz offers Istanbul diners a very rare thing indeed – a seaside restaurant that does not serve seafood. Instead, Kaşıbeyaz is a kebab house specializing in traditional Turkish cuisine from Gaziantep. It has become very popular with locals and visiting tourists who want to enjoy traditional Turkish food with a wonderful view of the Bosphorus.</string>
    <string name="kasibeyaz_bosphorus_address">Yeniköy Mahallesi, Köybaşı Cd. No:10, 34464 Sarıyer/İstanbul</string>

    <!-- hotels -->
    <string name="hilton_istanbul_bosphorus">Hilton Istanbul Bosphorus</string>
    <string name="hilton_istanbul_bosphorus_info">
        Hilton Istanbul Bosphorus is Turkey\'s first modern hotel built from the ground up in the
        aftermath of World War II in Europe. Currently, it is also titled with Hilton Hotels longest-serving
        member outside the United States.
        The Hilton Istanbul Bosphorus contains 499 air-conditioned rooms. In addition, the hotel offers
        158 executive rooms and 13 suites. For privileged guests, an executive lounge is reserved.
        There are 27 meeting rooms, open-air localities and a convention and exhibition center capable
        of holding 3,000 people. The business center is at 24/7 service. For wedding ceremonies and celebrations,
        the hotel garden offers place for up to 300 guests on weekdays.
    </string>
    <string name="hilton_istanbul_bosphorus_address">Harbiye Mahallesi, Cumhuriyet Cd. No:50, 34367 Şişli/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="swissotel_the_bosphorus">Swissotel The Bosphorus</string>
    <string name="swissotel_the_bosphorus_info">
        Swissotel The Bosphorus, Istanbul is a five-star luxury hotel right in the centre of Istanbul
        on the European banks of the Bosphorus. Nestled within 65 acres of historical gardens with
        world-class shopping and vibrant nightlife nearby, it offers 497 guest rooms and suites,
        featuring state-of-the-art technology and exclusive amenities. Last but not least, the award-winning
        Purovel Spa and Sport offers luxurious holistic spa treatments from all over the world.
    </string>
    <string name="swissotel_the_bosphorus_address">Vişnezade Mahallesi, Acısu Sokaği No:19, 34357 Beşiktaş/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="istanbul_marriot_hotel">İstanbul Marriott Hotel</string>
    <string name="istanbul_marriot_hotel_info">
        Offering an indoor pool, sauna, Turkish bath and a fitness centre, Istanbul Marriott Hotel Sisli
        is located in one of Istanbul\'s commerce centres.
    </string>
    <string name="istanbul_marriot_hotel_address">Merkez Mahallesi, Abide-i Hürriyet Cd No:142, 34381 Şişli/İstanbul</string>
    <string name="doubletree_by_hilton">DoubleTree by Hilton Istanbul - Moda</string>
    <string name="doubletree_by_hilton_info">
        With a beautiful view of the sea, the hotel is close to the ferry dock that allows guests to
        go from the quiet residential Moda area to the bustle of the European side.
    </string>
    <string name="doubletree_by_hilton_address">Caferağa Mahallesi, Albay Faik Sözdener Cd. No:31, 34710 Kadıköy/İstanbul
</string>

</resources>
